# Vladislav Romanciuc

**1** Leith Walk, Edinburgh, Scotland



✓ <u>vladislavromanciuc@gmail.com</u>



in <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/vladromanciuc/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/vladromanciuc/</a>



https://github.com/VladRomanciuc

## Summary

Creative nature paired with a logical approach and a broad range of transferable and interpersonal skills makes me always ready to absorb new ideas and choose effective solutions and quickly and efficiently solve problems.

My vast work experience alongside my technical knowledge in many other areas of Information Technology are resulting in the implementation of best practices in a friendly and positive demeanour maintaining the professionalism level.

Interested in Business Analytics, based on Data Science Methodologies with a drop of Design Thinking and blend of UX.

I'm involved in the Product Analytics 101 Program with The Product Folks Community!

The hobby projects to showcase my skills along are on my Github!

Currently learning paths:

On the way on my learning shelf are:

- IBM Data Science for Business;

- Reactive System, Microservices with GO;

Microsoft Data Analyst Associate;

- Web Apps with Dart and Flutter.

- Google Cloud Learning.

Looking to secure a position where I can use my outgoing personality, skills and develop new ones.

#### **Achievements**

- ➤ Deloitte Tech Consulting Virtual Internship (28-31/10/2021)
  - Cloud Engineering prepared a high-level overview of Cloud Computing for a client meeting, Cloud Feasibility and Cloud Readiness Assessments.
  - Technology Strategy & Innovation evaluated technology aspects for developing an online banking platform for a client, designed a business case including a high-level overview of the costs, benefits, and considerations and developed a high-level implementation plan and predict cost estimates.
  - Optimisation & Delivery conducted an initial market scan to evaluate and select a few financial accounting systems for the client, market evaluation to identify the best solution to client requirements with further analysis and solution presentation.

Skillset: Industry and Market Scan Research | Feasibility Assessment | Value and Benefit Analysis | Project Planning and Delivery | Cost Analysis and Estimation | Resource Management | Feasibility, Risk and Readiness Assessment | Communication | Presentation.

#### ➤ Accenture Project Management Virtual Experience (13-15/112021)

- Associated projects to the most suitable project management approach and prepared a streamlined proposal for the client.
- Created a status dashboard for the project and gave a presentation on updates of the project.

Skillset: Project Management | Strategic Analysis | Synthesizing | Communication | Presentation.

#### ➤ Accenture Nordics Consultant Program (12/11/2021)

- Defined project key priorities and assembled a project plan for a client.
- Analysed data from various sources and made decisions about UX Redesign.
- Assigned scores to potential initiatives based on their ease of implementation and impact.

Skillset: Planning | Prioritizing | Data analysis | Client relations.

#### ➤ Accenture UK Virtual Experience Program (07/11-11/11/2021)

- Identified opportunities to build a strategy using the agile methodology.
- Created a plan for management and completion of a project.
- Produced engaging marketing content for a new product.
- Investigated the product issues based on usage data analysis.

Skillset: Data Analysis | Project Management | Agile Methodology | User Stories | Marketing | Branding | Content Creation.

#### **▶ PwC Power BI Virtual Case Experience** (27/10/2021)

- Defined KPIs and created a Power BI Dashboard for a Call Centre to visualise customer and agent behaviour.
- Outlined relevant KPIs in hiring, promotion, performance and turnover for a client, designed a Power BI Dashboard and identified the root causes of their slow progress.

  Skillset: Defining KPIs | Power BI Dashboard | Insights and Actions | Calculating Measures.

### ➤ KPMG Data Analytics Virtual Experience Program (04-06/11/2021)

- Directed an Assessment of data quality and completeness for analysis.
- Projected high value customers based on customer demographics and attributes through visualisation of insights.

Skillset: Data Quality Analysis | Analytical Dashboard Creation | Customer Segmentation.

#### **▶ GE Digital Technology Data Analytics Program** (01-03/11/2021)

• Used data engineering to combine full-flight engine, part manufacturing and airport location data and create a KPI dashboard.

Skillset gained: Business Intelligence (BI) | Data orchestration & transformation | Postgres/SQL.

#### ➤ Smart Cities Virtual Start-up Internship Program (22-24/10/2021)

Credential: Sydney School of Entrepreneurship

Operated with start-ups that are leveraging the power of shared mobility, unlocking the distributed renewable energy network, and incentivising real, sustainable societal change:

- Liftango Developed a business expansion plan for the host organisation into the United States taking into account the concerns of various stakeholders and the constraints of available resources.
- SwitchDin Developed proposals and collateral to enhance communication of the host organisation's unique value proposition to a particular customer segment. Conduct personal reflections on how the proposed communication method impacts on the host organisation's customer experience
- GreenBe Developed a "Future Press Release" to communicate the benefits and key features of a proposed solution based off the host organisation's existing platform and capabilities.

Skillset: Customer Insights and Segmentation | Planning | Strategic and Critical Thinking | Risk Management | Stakeholder Management | Problem Identification and Investigation.

#### > Sydney Romantics Design & Branding Virtual Experience (25-26/10/2021)

➤ Created one blog article, two social media posts, 1 poster using Canva as a collaborative tool and identified 2 new creative ways to promote an event in the local area.

Skillset gained: Brand Analysis and Communication | Influencers and Social Media | Marketing and Event Ideation.

#### Certifications

Lean Six Sigma White Belt Certification | November 2021
 Issuing authority: Six Sigma Society | Credential ID: Yu1rKRAlCr

The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing | October 2021
 Issuing authority: Google Digital Garage | Credential ID: DWB 3WQ 7S9

Advanced Google Analytics | October 2021
 Issuing authority: Google Analytics Academy | Credential ID: mUoieCHzT5irDiAnzm3GsA

Cloud Digital Leader Learning Path | October 2021
 Issuing authority: Google Cloud Skills Boost | Credential ID: view badges

Agile Explorer | November 2021
 Issuing authority: IBM SkillsBuild for Students and Educators | Credential ID: Credly

Data Science Foundations - Level 2 (V2) | November 2021
 Issuing authority: IBM Cognitive Class | Credential ID: Credly

Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner | November 2021
 Issuing authority: IBM Design Global | Credential ID : Credly

Enterprise Design Thinking - Team Essentials for AI | November 2021
 Issuing authority: IBM Design Global | Credential ID : Credly

#### **Education**

08/2019 - 06/2021 Higher National Diploma in Tourism and Travel

SQA Grade: A (EQF level 5) | Edinburgh College, Scotland

Through an exceptional performance strengthened my grasp in Visitor Attractions Management, Guiding and Resort Representation, World Gastronomy Tourism achieving a maximum score of available credits and a National Qualification Award.

Developed a deep understanding of Airport and Airline Operations, Tour Operator Retail Operations and initiation in GDS Travelport, Amadeus, Sabre that guarantees a strong capacity to make a greater contribution and quick adaptation to this business segment.

Performed quality researches over detailed case studies in Marketing, Niche Markets and Digital Media in Travel Business displaying the ability to learn rapidly and maximise the benefits of Microsoft Office and Google Workspace tools and collaboration tools such as Zoom, Zoho Projects, Microsoft Teams.

#### 08/2018 - 06/2019 **Travel and Tourism SCQF level 6**

(EQF level 4) | Edinburgh College, Scotland

Gained a unique set of skills for the travel and tourism industry through teamwork and cooperative learning, presentations and role-plays that enhanced consultative selling skills, interpersonal and corporate relationship management, customer care and satisfaction tactics via digital channels using CRM HubSpot and social media management platform Hootsuite.

06/2017 - 06/2018 National 5 ESOL

SQA Grades: B | Edinburgh College, Scotland

## **Employment**

09/2016 - 11/2021 **Chef de Partie** 

Miller & Carter Edinburgh City Center (09/2019 – 11/2021)

Chaophraya Edinburgh (04/2017 – 08/2018) Wahaca Edinburgh (09/2016 – 04/2017)

Expanded the personal interest for culinary running food services mainly on a part-

time basis in Mexican, Thai cuisines and Classic Steakhouse.

Details: The natural resilience and ability to keep a cool head enabled the leadership qualities

to mentor and coach junior staff maintaining the upbeat atmosphere during crowded

services.

Efficiency in planning and prioritisation increased productivity while willingness to the

ongoing learning diverse creativity delivering memorable dining experiences.

Education: Professional Cookery, Food and Beverage Service IVQ Level 2 (01/2017 – 06/2018)

City & Guilds Distinction Diploma (EQF level 4) | Edinburgh College, Scotland

#### 10/2015 - 09/2016 **Travelling Mediterranean & Black Sea Coasts**

Restructured the established mindset and personal cultural views completing a planned scenic drive to explore the popular touristic destination of the Black Sea Coast (Crimea, Ukraine, Romania, Bulgaria) and Mediterranean Coast (Turkey, France, Spain).

Details: Constructively coped daily with a range of circumstances that stimulated verbal and

nonverbal eloquence to overcome foreign language and cultural barriers.

Challenged new places, people, situations and issues related to budgeting and planning that refined adaptability and negotiation tactics.

#### 04/2011 – 10/2015 Head of Operations and Interactions of Intelligence and Prevent Group

Chisinau Municipality Police Department, Moldova

The confidence in making decisions and dynamic leadership potential demonstrated senior executive ability and have advanced in a new role with higher responsibility.

Details: Effectively managed a special unit controlling investigative and supportive operations

necessary for the suppression of illegal activities using intelligence and information

for identification and localisation of potential threats.

Organised and coordinated the liaison with other services and authorities, linkages of security and enforcement, crisis intervention and negotiation teams for the effective

operation during unusual situations, diplomatic visits and mass events.

Education: Tracking, Surveillance and Defence Tactics (10/2014-11/2014)

International Cooperation and Coordination Agency, Ankara, Turkey

### 10/2005 - 04/2011 Principal Analysts of Public Safety Unit

Chisinau Municipality Police Department, Moldova

After a few years of efficient operations as a Police Officer, was promoted to a Principal

Analysts position in a Special Unit.

Details: Performed a variety of analytic reports based on statistical data predicting the

dynamics with relevant recommendations.

Created assessments on assigned tasks and targets interpreting data and classified

information in comprehensive reports identifying threats to public safety.

Education: Bachelor degree in Criminology and Criminal Justice and Law (09/2001 - 06/2005)

(EQF level 6) | Institute of Applicative and Integrative Law Studies, Chisinau

Municipality, Moldova

#### Languages

Details:

Available to operate at the highest level independently and in teams, in busy environments using my native Romanian and Russian languages and limited working proficiency (written business communication) in French and Spanish. These are valuable for getting insights from new emerging markets, establish and maintain professional business relationships and foreign exposure of the company. A common language guarantees customers and partners' loyalty offering the opportunity to expand the operations and stimulate revenue growth.